A Guide to the Wade Hampton Frost Collection 1880-1938; 1938-1984
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
Wade Hampton Frost Collection 1880-1938; 1938-1984
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-2
7.5 linear ft. (17 boxes, ca. 600 items); personal papers and publications 15 boxes 13 cm x 39.5 cm x 26.5 cm; framed photographs, scrapbook, and audiotapes 1 box 32.5 cm x 41 cm x 26.5 cm; artifacts 13 1 box 11 x 18 x 9.5 inches
Susan Frost Parrish, daughter of Wade Hampton Frost, collected information on her father and the rest of her family and donated her findings to the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library.
Administrative Information
Access
No restrictions
Biographical/Historical Information
A 1903 medical alumnus of the University of Virginia, Wade Hampton Frost (1880-1938) was a surgeon with the United States Public Health Service from 1905 to 1929. In 1919, he was assigned as resident lecturer to the new Johns Hopkins School of Hygiene and Public Health. In 1929, he resigned from the United States Public Health Service in order to serve full-time as professor of epidemiology at Johns Hopkins University. From 1931 to 1934, he was Dean of Johns Hopkins University School of Hygiene and Public Health.
Wade Hampton Frost was a pioneer in the study of water pollution. He also conducted important research on poliomyelitis, yellow fever, influenza, diptheria, and tuberculosis. Throughout his professional life, Frost emphasized development of the epidemiological method in the investigation of disease. His work helped transform epidemiology from a descriptive to an analytic science and contributed to the establishment of epidemiology as a distinct field of medical research.
Scope and Content Information
Historical Collections and Services houses seventeen boxes of Wade Hampton Frost materials. The Frost Collection includes personal and official correspondence, photographs, scientific publications, newspaper articles, taped interviews, and assorted memorabilia pertaining to Wade Hampton Frost and his family. Frost's daughter, Susan Frost Parrish, donated the collection to the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library in 1984 with added research notes. (It is noted that the maiden name of Susan Frost Parrish is Susan Haxall Frost which is also her mother's name. She is entered in our collection as Susan Frost Parrish).
Contents List
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ANNA BAETJER RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 24 June 1975, TMs with autograph corrections (Box-folder 01-001)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. MORTON LEVIN RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 25 June 1975, TMs with autograph corrections (Box-folder 01-002)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. JAMES PERKINS RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 27 June 1975, TMs (Box-folder 01-003)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. PHILIP E. SARTWELL RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 25 June 1975, TMs with autograph corrections (Box-folder 01-004)
- INTERVIEW WITH DR. ERNEST STEBBINS RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 24 June 1975, TMs with autograph corrections (Box-folder 01-005)
- RESEARCH NOTES OF BARRY P. RUTIZER RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST 1975 ca., TMs (Box-folder 01-006)
- "THE AMERICAN RED CROSS AS A PUBLIC HEALTH AUXILIARY" BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 1917-19 ca., TMs with autograph corrections (Box-folder 01-007)
  NOTE BY SUSAN FROST PARRISH FROM 1975 ATTACHED
- "OUTLINE OF PROPOSED ORGANIZATION AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE DEPARTMENT OF EPIDEMIOLOGY AT JOHNS HOPKINS" BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 8 November 1919, TMsS (electrostatic copy) (Box-folder 01-008)
- "WHAT EVERY HEALTH OFFICER SHOULD KNOW: EPIDEMIOLOGY," BY WADE HAMPTON FROST October 1937, 2 TMs with autograph corrections (electrostatic copies) (Box-folder 01-009)
- "REPORT OF PROGRESS IN STATISTICAL AND EPIDEMIOLOGICAL STUDIES OF INFLUENZA DURING FISCAL YEAR ENDING JUNE 30, 1918," BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 1919, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-010)
- "REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON ORGANIZATION AND DEVELOPMENT OF THE SCHOOL OF HYGIENE," BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 29 October 1931, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-011)
- REPORT OF COMMITTEE ON EPIDEMIOLOGY ND, TMs with autograph corrections (EC) (Box-folder 01-012)
- "HENRY ROSE CARTER." FOR INTERNATIONAL HEALTH BOARD REPORT 1925, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-013)
- "COMMENT ON CARTER MEMORIAL IN INTERNATIONAL HEALTH BOARD BULLETIN" BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 1926, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-014)
  RE: HENRY ROSE CARTER
- "MEMORANDUM OF CONVERSATION WITH FREDERICK F. RUSSELL," BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 8 July 1935, AMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-015)
- CONFERENCE IN SURGEON GENERAL HUGH S. CUMMING'S OFFICE--LIST OF THOSE PRESENT 31 July 1935, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-016)
  WADE HAMPTON FROST ON THE LIST
- LIST OF CONTRIBUTORS TO THE FROST MEMORIAL FUND ND, T list (EC) (Box-folder 01-017)
- UNTITLED POEM BY HARRIET FROST ND, AMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-018)
- "A POEM TO THE SUSANS FROST," BY MRS. HARTMAN HARRISON ND, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-019)
- JOHN W. OWEN'S EDITORIAL, "STOP, LOOK AND LISTEN," FOUND IN WADE HAMPTON FROST'S DESK AT HOME 16 October 1936, Newsclipping (Box-folder 01-020)
- RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST'S DEATH AND TRIBUTES TO HIS WORK 1938, newsclippings (EC) (Box-folder 01-021)
- JOHN W. OWENS'S DEATH NOTICE/EDITORIAL 24-26 April 1968, newsclipping (Box-folder 01-022)
- MISCELLANEOUS NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS AND THE JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY SCHOOL OF HYGIENE AND PUBLIC HEALTH ALUMNI BULLETIN PAGES 1923-75, newsclippings/TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-023)
- MISCELLANEOUS: UNIVERSITY OF VIRGINIA COURSE DESCRIPTIONS, WADE HAMPTON FROST BIRTH CERTIFICATE, TITLE PAGES, ARTICLES, ETC. 1880-1940, TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-024)
- MISCELLANEOUS REPRINTS BY WADE HAMPTON FROST, WILSON G. SMILLIE, HUNTINGTON WILLIAMS, AND ABRAHAM M. LILIENFELD 1935; 1953; 1961; 1973, 5 TMs (EC) (Box-folder 01-025)
- FAMILY TREE OF THOMAS C. FROST, ESQ. (WADE HAMPTON FROST'S ENGLISH ANCESTRY) mid-1400's to late 1700's, Photo/chart (Box-folder 01-026)
- PORTRAIT OF AN UNIDENTIFIED ANCESTOR OF WADE HAMPTON FROST ca. 1640, photo of portrait (Box-folder 01-027)
- NOTE FROM SUSAN F. PARRISH RE: PHOTOGRAPH 1989; 1665-1717, AMS (Box-folder 01-028)
  ORIGINAL PHOTOGRAPH NOTED AS BEQUEATHED TO SOUTH CAROLINA HISTORICAL COLLECTION
- NOTE FROM SUSAN F. PARRISH RE: FAMILY PHOTOGRAPH 1806; 1989, AMS (Box-folder 01-029)
- "THE FROST FAMILY IN AMERICA." AND BIBLIOGRAPHICAL NOTE FROM SUSAN FROST PARRISH 1989, AMS (Box-folder 01-030)
- "THE FROST FAMILY IN ENGLAND AND AMERICA" BY THOMAS AND EDWARD FROST 1909, 1 AMs; 1 TD (Box-folder 01-031)
  WITH NOTE ON BIBLIOGRAPHIC DATA
- "IN MEMORIAM--HENRY FROST AND SABRA J. WALKER FROST," IN THE PARISH LEAFLET May 1917, TD (Box-folder 01-032)
- "PAMPHLET: THE MILES BREWTON," OWNED BY WADE HAMPTON FROST'S COUSINS 1920's ca., TMs (Box-folder 01-033)
- GREENVILLE NEWS: ACCOUNT OF S.C. SCHOOL FOR DEAF & BLIND FOUNDED BY WADE HAMPTON FROST'S GRANDFATHER 30 December 1923, newsclipping (EC) (Box-folder 01-034)
- LETTER FROM FRANK FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST; OCTOBER ISSUE OF SOUTH CAROLINA HISTORICAL AND GENEALOGICAL MAGAZINE; NOTE BY SUSAN FROST PARRISH "1926-27, 1984", 3 TD (Box-folder 01-035)
- OHIO CHRONICLE: DR. NEWTON WALKER (UNCLE OF WADE HAMPTON FROST) NOMINATION BY PRESIDENT OF GAULLAUDET COLLEGE ND, newsclipping (Box-folder 01-036)
  MISSING AS OF 10-10-96 JMT
- "THE PALMETTO LEAF": MEMORIAL EDITION RE: NEWTON F. WALKER, SCHOOL SUPERINTENDENT AND UNCLE OF WADE HAMPTON FROST 26 February 1927, newsclipping (EC) (Box-folder 01-037)
- "TRIBUTE PAID TO A COUNTRY DOCTOR" RE: HENRY FROST, WADE HAMPTON FROST'S FATHER; NOTE BY SUSAN FROST PARRISH 1931 ca., newsclipping (EC) (Box-folder 01-038)
- HANDWRITTEN PARTIAL FAMILY TREE BY WADE HAMPTON FROST 1932 ca., AMs (Box-folder 01-039)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HORACE C. FROST, ENGLISH COUSIN, RE: COMMON ANCESTRY 5 April 1933, AMS (Box-folder 01-040)
- LETTER FROM HORACE C. FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST, RE: COMMON ANCESTOR, REVEREND FROST 8 February 1934, AMS (Box-folder 01-041)
- LETTER FROM HORACE C. FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST; NOTE BY S.F. PARRISH 1 October 1942; Nov. 1984, 1 AMS; 1 TMS (Box-folder 01-042)
- LETTER FROM ARTHUR F. STOCKER TO FRANK BERKELEY RE: WADE HAMPTON FROST'S GREAT-GRANDFATHER; NOTE BY S.F. PARRISH Feb. 1966; Nov. 1984, 2 TMS (Box-folder 01-043)
- GENEALOGICAL MATERIALS ON FAMILY OF WADE HAMPTON FROST ND, "newsclippings, articles, etc. (EC)" (Box-folder 01-044)
  SOME MATERIALS ARE DOUBLES FROM PREVIOUS FOLDERS
- GENEALOGICAL MATERIALS ON FAMILY OF SUSAN HAXALL FROST ND, "newsclippings, charts (EC)" (Box-folder 01-045)
- "200 YEAR OLD [NOLAND] HOUSE THAT WAS NEVER COMPLETED," ARTICLE PUBLISHED IN WASHINGTON STAR PICTORIAL MAGAZINE ND, newsclipping (Box-folder 01-046)
- ARTICLE RE: SUSAN HAXALL FROST'S GRANDFATHER'S HOUSE IN RICHMOND; NOTE BY S.F. PARRISH 1984; ND, 1 AMS; 1 newsclipping (Box-folder 01-047)
- ARTICLE "TRAVELERS' NOTES" RE: REDLANDS AND CARTER FAMILY; NOTE BY S.F. PARRISH 1984; ND, 1 TMS; 1 newsclipping (Box-folder 01-048)
- NOLAND FAMILY TREE, PARTIAL 1650-1950, AMs (Box-folder 01-049)
- HAXALL FAMILY TREE June 1931, AMs (Box-folder 01-050)
  COMPILED FOR HAXALL REUNION
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO J. TRIPLETT HAXALL 21 March 1935, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 02-001)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HARRY H. MOORE 11 March 1938, TL (Box-folder 02-002)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO WILLIAM H. WELCH 1919-1933, 7 TLS; 4 ALS; 1 telegram (EC) (Box-folder 02-003)
  FROM JOHNS HOPKINS MEDICAL LIBRARY ARCHIVES
- TENTH ANNIVERSARY MEMORIAL TRIBUTE TO WADE HAMPTON FROST; LETTERS TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST FROM FORMER STUDENTS AND FRIENDS OF WADE HAMPTON FROST April-May 1948, 35 TLS; 2 ALS (EC) (Box-folder 02-004)
  PRESENTED BY REGINALD ATWATER
- NOTE FROM SUSAN HAXALL FROST TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 1957 October, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 02-005)
- LETTER FROM SUSAN HAXALL FROST TO WILLIAM H. WELCH 21 August 1933, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 02-006)
- LETTER FROM SUSAN HAXALL FROST TO CONTRIBUTORS TO WADE HAMPTON FROST TENTH MEMORIAL TRIBUTE 5 June 1948, TL (EC) (Box-folder 02-007)
- LETTER FROM EDWARD S. GODFREY, JR. TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 1938 September, ALS (Box-folder 02-008)
- LETTER FROM LOUIS P. HAMBURGER, THOMAS S. CULLEN, ANDREW G. GILLIS, ARTHUR M. SHIPLEY, ARTHUR G. BARRETT, HUNTINGTON WILLIAMS ET AL., CONSULTANTS TO BALTIMORE CITY HEALTH DEPARTMENT TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH ON HER WEDDING DAY 16 Feb. 1944, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 02-009)
- POST CARD FROM VICTOR G. HERBER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 7 Nov. 1916, APCS (Box-folder 02-010)
  SENT FROM JAPAN
- CHRISTMAS CARD FROM DR. AND MRS. EUGENIO HERNANDO TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 1930 Nov, christmas card (EC) (Box-folder 02-011)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. HOWELL TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 20 Feb. 1939, ALS (Box-folder 02-012)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. HOWELL TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 20 Feb. 1942, ALS (Box-folder 02-013)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. HOWELL TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 10 Oct. 1942, ALS (Box-folder 02-014)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. HOWELL TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 21 Feb 1943, ALS (Box-folder 02-015)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. HOWELL TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 14 Feb. 1944, ALS (Box-folder 02-016)
- LETTER FROM BRIGADIER GENERAL EDGAR E. HUME TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 20 May 1949, TLS (Box-folder 02-017)
- LETTER FROM C. HAMPSON JONES TO WADE HAMPTON FROST [192- or 193-], ALS (Box-folder 02-018)
- LETTER FROM PEARL L. KENDRICK TO ERNEST L. STEBBINS RE: HIS LETTER OF 1 MAY 1958 6 May 1958, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 02-019)
  TWENTIETH ANNIVERSARY OF DEATH OF WADE HAMPTON FROST
- LETTER FROM JAMES P. LEAKE TO RICHARD M. SMITH 16 Feb 1938, TLS (Box-folder 02-020)
- LETTER FROM MORTON L. LEVIN TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 10 March 1973, ALS (Box-folder 02-021)
- LETTER FROM KENNETH F. MAXCY TO HARRIET FROST 7 Oct. 1940, TLS (Box-folder 02-022)
- LETTER FROM KENNETH F. MAXCY TO HARRIET FROST 21 June 1941, TLS (Box-folder 02-023)
- LETTER FROM KENNETH F. MAXCY TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 21 July 1941, ALS (Box-folder 02-024)
- LETTER FROM KENNETH F. MAXCY TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 23 Oct. 1941, ALS (Box-folder 02-025)
- LETTER FROM CHARLES T. MAITLAND TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 9 Sept. 1931, ALS (Box-folder 02-026)
- LETTER FROM CHARLES L. MINOR TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 29 April 1918, TLS (Box-folder 02-027)
- LETTER FROM HARRY H. MOORE TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 28 Feb. 1938, TLS (Box-folder 02-028)
- LETTER FROM SALLIE MUSTARD [MRS. HARRY S. MUSTARD] TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 19 June 1965, ALS (Box-folder 02-029)
  RE: RELATIONSHIP WITH SUSAN HAXALL FROST AND WADE HAMPTON FROST
- LETTER FROM SIR ARTHUR NEWSHOLME TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 22 July 1921, ALS (Box-folder 02-030)
- LETTER FROM SIR ARTHUR NEWSHOLME TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 24 Feb. 1923, ALS (Box-folder 02-031)
- LETTER FROM SIR ARTHUR NEWSHOLME TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 13 Sept. 1938, ALS (Box-folder 02-032)
- LETTER FROM LOUIS P. HAMBURGER, THOMAS S. CULLEN, ANDREW G. GILLIS, ARTHUR M. SHIPLEY, ARTHUR G. BARRETT, HUNTINGTON WILLIAMS ET AL., CONSULTANTS TO BALTIMORE CITY HEALTH DEPARTMENT, TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH ON HER WEDDING DAY 16 Feb. 1944, TLS (Box-folder 02-033)
  FRIENDS AND ASSOCIATES OF WADE HAMPTON FROST
- REVIEW OF KENNETH F. MAXCY'S "PAPERS OF WADE HAMPTON FROST" BY MARGERY T. OVERHOLSER ca. 1941, 5 TD (Box-folder 02-034)
  "KENNETH F. MAXCY, EDITOR"
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 18 April 1936, ALS (Box-folder 02-035)
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 8 May 1938, ALS (Box-folder 02-036)
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 9 March 1940, ALS (Box-folder 02-037)
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 27 Mar. 1940, ALS (Box-folder 02-038)
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 19 June 1940, ALS (Box-folder 02-039)
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 18 Aug. 1941, ALS (Box-folder 02-040)
- LETTER FROM JOHN W. OWENS TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 8 Sept. 1941, ALS (Box-folder 02-041)
- LETTER FROM EDWARDS A. PARK TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 27 Dec. 1933, ALS (Box-folder 02-042)
- LETTER FROM EDWARDS A. PARK TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 16 Jan. 1958, TLS (Box-folder 02-043)
- LETTER FROM EDWARDS A. PARK TO ERNEST L. STEBBINS 1958, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 02-044)
- LETTER FROM MILTON J. ROSENAU TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 23 Mar. 1938, TLS (Box-folder 02-045)
- LETTER FROM MILTON J. ROSENAU TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 2 April 1938, TLS (Box-folder 02-046)
- LETTER FROM MILTON J. ROSENAU TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 16 Feb. 1938, 2 pencil sketches (Box-folder 02-047)
- LETTER FROM SUSAN FROST PARRISH TO B. RUTIZER RE: SUGGESTIONS FOR SOURCES ON WADE HAMPTON FROST 1 June 1975, AL (EC) (Box-folder 02-048)
- LETTER FROM JOHN R. PAUL TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 2 Nov. 1956, TLS (Box-folder 02-049)
- LETTER FROM HAROLD ROTH TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 27 Jan. 1917, ALS (Box-folder 02-050)
  FORMER EMPLOYEE AT STREAM POLLUTION STATION IN CINCINNATI
- LETTER FROM MARY K. SEDGWICK TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 26 Feb. 1921, ALS (Box-folder 02-051)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM T. SEDGWICK TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 27 Dec. 1914, ALS (Box-folder 02-052)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM T. SEDGWICK TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 26 Dec. 1914, ALS (Box-folder 02-053)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM T. SEDGWICK TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 29 June 1916, ALS (Box-folder 02-054)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM T. SEDGWICK TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 16 Nov. 1917, TLS (Box-folder 02-055)
- LETTER FROM ERNEST L. STEBBINS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 27 March 1973, TLS (Box-folder 02-056)
- LETTER FROM ERNEST L. STEBBINS TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 27 Feb. 1976, ALS (Box-folder 02-057)
  RE: BORROWED PHOTO OF WADE HAMPTON FROST AND DR. L. REED
- LETTER FROM LEWIS R. THOMPSON TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 28 Oct. 1942, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 02-058)
- LETTER FROM FREDERIC C. WALCOTT TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 13 June 1934, TLS (Box-folder 02-059)
  RE: RELATIONSHIP BETWEEN WILLIAM H. WELCH AND WADE HAMPTON FROST
- LETTER FROM NEWTON F. WALKER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 23 Mar. 1923, TLS (Box-folder 02-060)
  "RE: DEATH OF THOMAS LOWNDES FROST, BROTHER OF WADE HAMPTON FROST"
- LETTER FROM NEWTON F. WALKER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 27 Dec. 1927, TLS (Box-folder 02-061)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. WELCH TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 11 Jan. 1929, ALS (Box-folder 02-062)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. WELCH TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 18 Jan. 1929, ALS (Box-folder 02-063)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. WELCH TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 16 May 1932, ALS (Box-folder 02-064)
- LETTER FROM WILLIAM H. WELCH TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 21 Sept. 1933, ALS (Box-folder 02-065)
- LETTER FROM J.M. WHEELIS, JR. TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 7 Mar. 1938, TLS (Box-folder 02-066)
- LETTER FROM HUNTINGTON WILLIAMS TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 27 Oct. 1939, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 02-067)
- LETTER FROM REGINALD M. ATWATER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 20 Nov. 1921, TLS (Box-folder 03-001)
  SENT FROM PEKING
- LETTER FROM REGINALD M. ATWATER TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 12 Sept. 1938, TLS (Box-folder 03-002)
- LETTER FROM REGINALD M. ATWATER TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 24 May 1949, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-003)
- LETTER FROM GEORGE A. AUDEN TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 17 Sept. 1933, ALS (Box-folder 03-004)
- LETTER FROM GEORGE A. AUDEN TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 5 Dec. 1933, ALS (Box-folder 03-005)
- LETTER FROM EUGENE L. BISHOP TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 13 Sept. 1938, TLS (Box-folder 03-006)
- LETTER FROM EUGENE L. BISHOP TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 19 May 1949, TLS (Box-folder 03-007)
- LETTER FROM WYNDHAM B. BLANTON TO LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER 21 June 1929, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-008)
  FROM ALDERMAN LIBRARY COLLECTION
- LETTER FROM ISAIAH BOWMAN TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 30 July 1942, TLS (Box-folder 03-009)
- LETTER FROM JOHN S. BRYAN TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 25 Sept. 1936, TLS (Box-folder 03-010)
  "JOHN S. BRYAN, PRESIDENT OF VIRGINIA HISTORICAL SOCIETY"
- LETTER FROM FRANK A. CALDERONE TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 23 May 1938, TLS (Box-folder 03-011)
- LETTER FROM HENRY ROSE CARTER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST "1922, 1924", TL & TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-012)
- INSCRIPTION FROM LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST Sept. 1931, "ALS, TD (EC)" (Box-folder 03-013)
  "TITLE PAGE OF CARTER'S BOOK, EDITED BY WADE HAMPTON FROST AND LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER"
- LETTERS FROM LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 1928-1930, 31 TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-014)
- LETTER FROM LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER TO WYNDHAM B. BLANTON 23 June 1929, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-015)
- LETTER FROM LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER TO FREDERICK F. RUSSELL 18 June 1928, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-016)
- POEM: "A BALLADE OF BRAVE LADYES," BY LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER ND, TMS (Box-folder 03-017)
  FOR SUSAN FROST PARRISH
- LETTER FROM JAMES H. CASSEDY TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 12 Oct. 1957, TLS (Box-folder 03-018)
- LETTER FROM JAMES H. CASSEDY TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 16 May 1961, TLS (Box-folder 03-019)
- LETTER FROM CHARLES V. CHAPIN TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 3 Feb. 1924, ALS (Box-folder 03-020)
- LETTER FROM ANTONIO CIOCCO TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 2 May 1938, ALS (Box-folder 03-021)
  CONDOLENCES
- LETTER FROM JANET HOWELL CLARK TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 17 Feb. 1965, ALS (Box-folder 03-022)
- LETTER FROM BARBARA S. QUIN TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 15 Oct. 1938, TLS (Box-folder 03-023)
  COMMONWEALTH FUND
- LETTER FROM GEDDES SMITH TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 28 Jan. 1941, ALS (Box-folder 03-024)
- LETTER FROM GEDDES SMITH TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 17 July 1941, TLS (Box-folder 03-025)
- LETTER FROM GEDDES SMITH TO SUSAN PARRISH FROST 11 Sept. 1941, TLS (Box-folder 03-026)
- LETTER FROM GEDDES SMITH TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 10 June 1943, TLS (Box-folder 03-027)
- LETTER FROM GEDDES SMITH TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 28 June 1943, ALS (Box-folder 03-028)
- LETTER FROM GRAHAM R. TAYLOR TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 25 Jan. 1939, TLS (Box-folder 03-029)
- LETTER FROM GRAHAM R. TAYLOR TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 21 Aug. 1941, TLS (Box-folder 03-030)
- LETTER FROM POLLY LEAKE CRAVEN TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 18 March 1973, ALS (Box-folder 03-031)
- LETTER FROM RICHARD H. CREEL TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 12 Sept. 1938, ALS (Box-folder 03-032)
- LETTER FROM HUGH S. CUMMING TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 1921-31, 8 TLS; 5 TL (EC) (Box-folder 03-033)
  FROM ALDERMAN LIBRARY COLLECTION; HUGH S. CUMMING: SURGEON GENERAL OF THE UNITED STATES
- LETTER FROM HUGH S. CUMMING TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 12 July 1922, ALS (Box-folder 03-034)
  HUGH S. CUMMING: SURGEON GENERAL OF THE UNITED STATES
- LETTER FROM HUGH S. CUMMING TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 20 June 1929, ALS (Box-folder 03-035)
- LETTER FROM HUGH S. CUMMING, JR. TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 23 Feb. 1972, "ALS & printed memoir, signed" (Box-folder 03-036)
  ENCLOSURE: RECOLLECTIONS OF A CHILDHOOD IN NOTTOWAY BY LUCY BOOTH CUMMING
- LETTER FROM J.A. DOULL TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 16 July 1940, TLS (Box-folder 03-037)
- LETTER FROM J.A. DOULL TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 18 Oct. 1940, TLS (EC) (Box-folder 03-038)
- LETTER FROM THOMAS UNDERWOOD DUDLEY TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 13 Feb. 1938, ALS (Box-folder 03-039)
  THOMAS UNDERWOOD DUDLEY: BROTHER-IN-LAW OF WADE HAMPTON FROST
- LETTER FROM HAVEN EMERSON, W.S. LEATHERS & WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HUGH S. CUMMING 1 Aug. 1935, TL (CC) (Box-folder 03-040)
- LETTER FROM HAVEN EMERSON TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 26 Nov. 1938, ALS (Box-folder 03-041)
- LETTER FROM J.G. FITZGERALD TO SUSAN HAXALL FROST 13 Oct. 1938, ALS (Box-folder 03-042)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 31 July 1913, ALS (Box-folder 03-043)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 13 Sept. 1913, ALS (Box-folder 03-044)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 22 Jan. 1915, ALS (Box-folder 03-045)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 6 Apr. 1916, ALS (Box-folder 03-046)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 24 Nov. 1915, ALS (Box-folder 03-047)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 26 Nov. 1915, ALS (Box-folder 03-048)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 8 Dec. 1915, ALS (Box-folder 03-049)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 27 May 1916, ALS (Box-folder 03-050)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 2 Oct. 1916, ALS (Box-folder 03-051)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 10 Oct. 1916, ALS (Box-folder 03-052)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 3 Nov. 1916, ALS (Box-folder 03-053)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 26 Dec. 1916, ALS (Box-folder 03-054)
- LETTER FROM HENRY FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 1 Jan. 1917, APCS (Box-folder 03-055)
- LETTER FROM HORACE C. FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 8 Feb. 1934, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 03-056)
- LETTER FROM HORACE C. FROST TO WADE HAMPTON FROST 1 Dec. 1942, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 03-057)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO MRS. J. M. RAMEY 10 Nov. 1895, ALS (Box-folder 03-058)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO JOHN T. RAMEY 29 Nov. 1895, ALS (Box-folder 03-059)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO JOHN T. RAMEY 15 Nov. 1897, ALS (Box-folder 03-060)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO JOHN T. RAMEY 28 March 1898, ALS (Box-folder 03-061)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HENRY ROSE CARTER 1922-25, "9 TLS, 1 ALS (EC)" (Box-folder 03-062)
  FROM HENRY ROSE CARTER COLLECTION AT ALDERMAN LIBRARY
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO LAURA ARMISTEAD CARTER 1927-1930, "9 TLS, 1 TL (EC)" (Box-folder 03-063)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HUGH S. CUMMING 1921-1929, "8 TLS, 3 ALS (EC)" (Box-folder 03-064)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HUGH S. CUMMING 16 July 1922, TL (CC) (Box-folder 03-065)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HUGH S. CUMMING 8 Aug. 1935, TL (CC); TD (EC) (Box-folder 03-066)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO [] 4 Jan. 1933, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 03-067)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO [] 4 Jan. 1933, AL (Box-folder 03-068)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO HORACE C. FROST 5 April 1933, ALS (EC) (Box-folder 03-069)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 4 July 1920, ALS (Box-folder 03-070)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 14 Aug. 1933, ALS (Box-folder 03-071)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 17 Aug. 1933, ALS (Box-folder 03-072)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 3 Nov. 1937, ALS (Box-folder 03-073)
- LETTER FROM WADE HAMPTON FROST TO SUSAN FROST PARRISH 14 Nov. 1937, ALS (Box-folder 03-074)